

I've contributed and led teams for almost every user facing function: UI/UX design, research, testing, front end development etc; from enterprise to start up and everything in between. I've spent my career obsessing over how people interact with technology in order to create beautiful, efficient, testable products with the data to prove it.

Experience

Director of Product Design

Sept 2018 - Jan 2020

Team App | Tuesday Company

Established and led design, testing and data programs

Created channels to facilitate communication across multiple teams

Taught members of business units how to collect, write and document client/user insights and facilitated meetings to turn those into actionable ideas and give them priority

Trained team of designers and design interns to create appropriate prototypes, manage and work within design systems, run moderated user testing, perform client interviews, write case studies and documentation, recruit for user tests, participate in and run design sprints as well as mentored them along whatever continued learning path they chose including learning fe development and deploying full features

Created atomic architecture for design team that I then mirrored within the application environment to create a common language for designers and developers

Continued to contribute on an individual basis to large or key product features and development initiatives

Lead Designer / Front end Dev

Nov 2015 - Oct 2018

2015

Rackspace Hosting

Lead designer for global web site, charged with establishing the design initiative and instilling the importance of design-led thinking

Managed the entire look & feel, user journey, IA and conversion funnel of the global customer-facing site based on iterative user testing and data collection which I presented to executive stakeholders

Primary contributor and stakeholder for our living style guide, including managing and maintaining documentation

Part of lean growth team focused on leveraging UX research, testing and analytics to iterate designs, page flow & UI which improved customer experience and conversion rates

Application Designer / Developer

esigner / Developer

AT&T

UX Designer / Developer 2014

Mason Zimbler

Junior Developer 2013

Gray Digital Group

phone: (210) 860-4800 email: amber.r.rucker@gmail.com website: amberdoesdesign.com twitter: @amberdoesdesign

Skills

Things I Believe In

github: amberRrucker

Iterative Design, Atomic Design, moderated testing for every prototype, remote work works, design systems, understand the platform architecture, IA, be your devs best friend, document everything, everyone is a designer, nobody knows the client like support, there isn't one tool or platform to rule them all - be flexible, mentorship is our responsibility, MaintainableCSS, Angular commit messages, continuing data collection, proving your work

Design

UI, UX, IA, CX, Design Ops, Establishing teams and functions, User Testing & Research, Design Sprints, Iterative Design

Development

Native, Mobile, Web, Desktop, HTML5, CSS3, JS, SCSS/Less, MaintainableCSS, Bootstrap, Foundation, Wordpress, VVV, Jade, EJS, React Native, StorybookJS, living styleg guide

Tooling

Figma, JIRA, Studio, Sketch, Abstract, Atom, Coda, Data Studio, VWO, Git, Airtable, Zapier

Education

BFA - Communication Design Texas State University 2008 - 2012